Leeya Davis

🞙 New York City 🛮 leeya463@gmail.com 🖈 leeyadavis.dev 🔘 LeeyaD

I am a software engineer with multiple years of experience with Ruby, Javascript, various front-end and back-end frameworks, and other technologies. I am a co-creator of Twine &, an open-source solution for managing WebSockets at scale with connection state recovery.



EXPERIENCE

Co-Creator, Software Engineer, Twine \varnothing

08/2023 - present

Twine is a scalable drop-in Real-time as a Service that abstracts away the complexity of real-time communication and provides connection state recovery

- Prototyped and built Twine using TypeScript, Socket.IO, and Amazon Web Services (DynamoDB, Elasticache for Redis, EC2, ALB, ELB, CloudFront, S3)
- Drafted solution architecture and initial workflow diagrams
- Designed and implemented short and long-term storage strategies that facilitate connection state recovery
- Improved long-term state recovery by engineering a more performant database query
- Resolved synchronization issues when scaling Twine by implementing Redis Adaptor logic
- Streamlined the process of purging outdated data from Redis through automation (via cron jobs)
- Designed and built Twine's object-oriented client and server libraries; published as NPM packages
- · Assisted in the design of the CLI tool that using AWS CloudFormation automates the deployment of Twine and its provisioned AWS cloud infrastructure (Elastic Beanstalk Environment, EC2 instances, Application Load Balancer, IAM roles)
- Collaborated remotely with an international team of four engineers across three time zones
- Authored a technical case study providing an in-depth analysis of Twine's problem domain, system design, and engineering decisions (https://twine-realtime.github.io/#four)

Software Engineer, Self-Employed

07/2022 - 08/2023

- Request Inspect Tool for viewing/debugging webhooks (WebSocket server, Nginx, MongoDB, Express, React).
- Contact Manager Tool for managing contacts, incl. dynamic filtering (DO Droplets, Nginx, MongoDB, Express, React).
- Todo Tracker A DB-backed, single-page app for managing todos (Ruby, PostgreSQL, Sinatra, ERB).

Data Processing Coordinator, NYC Department of Health

12/2019 - 07/2022

- Coordinated with Opioid Overdose Prevention Programs (OOPPs) to receive, process, and track all monthly report components, resolving any issues encountered
- Supported data entry and data management of all monthly report components

SKILLS

Front End

JavaScript, React, HTML/CSS, Typescript, Handlebars, Sinatra

Misc. Technologies

Git/Github, Docker, OOP, Nginx, VS Code, Redis, Jest, Webhooks, HTTP, WebSockets, Postman, Mongoose, Bash

Back End

Node.js, Ruby, Express, SQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, REST APIs, TypeScript, Go

MongoDB Atlas, AWS (DynamoDB, Elasticache for Redis, EC2, ALB, ELB, CloudFront, IAM, S3), DigitalOcean droplets, Heroku, Fly.io

EDUCATION

Launch School, https://launchschool.com/employers ∂

08/2019 - 08/2023

Launch School is a multi-year, mastery-based software engineering curriculum. Progression is assessment-driven via 3-4 hours long written exams and live coding interviews aimed at developing problem-solving skills.